

Evgeny Denisov

Male, born on July 27, 1989

E-mail: evgenij.denisov@gmail.com

Telegram: tg://resolve?domain=el71Gato — preferred means of communication

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/evgeny-denisov-748b10129

GitHub: https://github.com/elGato

Citizenship: Russia. Current location: Montenegro. Willing to relocate to EU. **Desired position: Technical Game Designer**

Employment: full time, flexible schedule.

Skills: Services integration, Web API.

Technologies: Python, Django, aiohttp, FastAPI, Git, Gitlab, CI/CD, Linux, OpenAPI, Docker, PostgreSQL,

SQL, Redis, RabbitMQ, Kafka, gRPC, ProtoBuf.

About me: I enjoy adding new features into existing software with high attention to details. Besides Python, I have some knowledge in other programming languages and game engines: C++ (UE), C# (Unity), JavaScript (Phaser). When I play video games and see some intersting mechanics, I always think: "How would I implement it? How could I improve it? How can I exploit or break it?" (the last question is from my QA experience). I believe I am capable of both inventing and implementing game mechanics. This is why I decided to change my field of activity.

Work experience (> 6 years total)

July 2020 - February 2023 (2 years 7 months)

Zubr Saint Petersburg, zubr.io

Software Developer (FastAPI, gRPC, Kafka)

Together with a team I maintained a cryptocurrency derivative exchange. It was a complex ecosystem of services with asynchronous data flow. I maintained a dozen services and made several new ones. When the exchange experienced a critical data error that could have cost the company several BTC, I modified several services to maintain data consistency even after such errors.

September 2018 – April 2020 (1 year 8 months)

HCF Bank Saint Petersburg, market.homecredit.ru

Software Developer / ML Specialist (Django, Celery, PostgreSQL, Keras)

With a team I maintained an installment goods marketplace. We were splitting a monolith codebase into services and microservices. I removed a neural network from the feed parsing to speed up the process from several minutes to several seconds per feed. I also reworked a 200 lines SQL query that nobody remembered how it works to speed it up from 20 to 7 minutes and made it readable.

January 2018 – June 2018 (6 months)

Avatarico Saint Petersburg, avatarico.com

Software Developer / ML Specialist (DRF, NLTK, PyTorch)

Being a sole Python developer and ML specialist in the company, I self-studied both professions and developed an entertaining artificial neural network imitating a chat user.

December 2015 - October 2017 (1 year 10 months)

220 Volt Saint Petersburg, www.220-volt.ru

QA Engineer (Postman, Yandex.Tank, pytest)

As a proactive member of the team, I both checked new functionality and made proposals about adding/removing/modifying the product features. When I had no tasks to check, I was writing autotests and dabbling into new technologies. This way I adopted and introduced Gitlab CI and Docker before they went mainstream.

Education

Higher (2013): South Federal University, Information Security Faculty, Telecom Information Security.